Ryan Zelazny

355 Davies Ave Apt 2 West Henrietta NY 14586 (585) 736-2937

RyanZelazny@gmail.com

Summary

An experienced full stack software developer with expertise at whole process improvement.

Technical Skills: React.js, Express.js, Node.js, JavaScript, Typescript, SQL, Mongo, Jest/TDD, HTML, CSS, StepWise, ASP.NET, VBA, Databases, Microsoft Excel, Software Development Life Cycle, GitHub, Azure boards, Figma, Jira, AWS, AgilePlace, IIS, SOAP APIs, RESTful APIs

Professional Work Experience

Nexient 2021 – Present

Software Developer

Client: Fortune 500 Shipping Company

• Connecting Azure Dev ops boards to AgilePlace via LeanKit

Client: Law Firm

- Developed document locker functionality and production data fixes
- Assisted team with almost complete refactor of existing code base.
- React Styleguidist frontend, Node.js backend, SQL data updates.

Client: Fortune 500 Manufacturing Company

- Developed catalog pages and store checkout process. From cart to shipping/billing to confirmation
- Created reusable components to fast-track future site development from Figma designs
- Azure DevOps to AWS migration.
- React, Gatsby framework, and bit component technologies.

United Healthcare 2018 – 2020

StepWise Developer

- Led StepWise development and production deployments
- Volunteered to build new issue tracking and dev workflow system to improve release process
- Developed web-based batch tool to replace Excel process. Streamlined process, improved efficiency and eliminated server crashes
- Utilized MS SQL Server and StepWise suite of tools including HTML/CSS based Portal Designer

Excellus BCBS 2012 – 2018

Software Engineer

- Oversaw StepWise development via Formula Designer and Portal Designer
- Collected requirements from end users to create workflows for sales, underwriting, and product development teams
- Led process for NYS Exchange product data load and SBC document creation
- Provided large data analysis via SQL and SAS Enterprise Guide
- Utilized SOAP APIs, ASP.NET, IIS

Excellus BCBS 2010 – 2012

Underwriting Support

- Provided internal customer support as a StepWise super user
- Developed Excel/VBA tools

Open Source Work

Online Gaming Platform POC

- Full MERN stack application React/Reactstrap frontend, MongoDB, Express, and Node backend with Passport authentication and bcrypt password hashing
- Utilizes webcam and websockets to stream video and images to multiple players
- Acted as team lead

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Amazon Web Services

Education

Rutgers University

MERN Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

Pennsylvania State University

BS, Information Science and Technology